A Guide to the Wise County (Va.) Records, circa 1850-1980, undated
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Wise County (Va.) Records, circa 1850-1980, undated
The Library of Virginia
1016223-1016284
22 boxes
Wise County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These boxes came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court records from Wise County.
Historical Information
Wise County was named for Henry Alexander Wise, governor of Virginia from 1856-1860. The county was formed in 1856 from Lee, Scott and Russell counties.
Scope and Content
Wise County (Va.) Records, circa 1850-1980, undated, consist of the following series: Court Records (subfield series include Criminal Records, Judgments, Clerks' Records, Chancery Records and Jury Records), Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, Tax and Fiscal Records, Fiduciary Records, Military and Pension Records, Election Records, Organization Records, County Administrative Records (subfield series include Treasurers' Records, Board of Supervisors Records, Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records and Overseers of the Poor Records), School Records, Business Records, Land Records, Miscellaneous Records and Marriage Records and Vital Statistics.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Wise County Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm" found on the Library of Virginia's web site.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Wise County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records--Virginia--Wise County.
Geographical Names:
Wise County (Va.)--History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Wise County.
Contents List
- Records, 1889-1964
  Court Records: Criminal Records: Indictments, Judgments; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Tax and Fiscal Records; Fiduciary Records: Military and Pension Records: Confederate Widow Pension Applications; Election Records.
- Records, 1892-1935
  Court Records: Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes; Tax an Fiscal Records.
- Records, 1870-1910
  Court Records: Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes, Judgments; Organization Records: Knights of Pythias Virginia Convention Proceedings, 1904 Feb.); County Administrative Records: Treasurers' Records; Tax and Fiscal Records. No chancery found.
- Records, 1875-1915
  Court Records: Criminal Records, Judgments, Clerks' Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Election Records, 1901; School Records, 1907; Organization Records. Chancery pulled.
- Records, 1884-1930
  Court Records: Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes, 1884-1900, Clerk's Records, (Record of Cases), 1899, Chancery Records; Election Records, 1928-1930; Business Records(2 bound volumes, hauling lumber account book), 1903-1905. Pre-1914 chancery pulled.
- Records, 1865-1915; 1935
  County Administrative Record: Board of Supervisors Records, 1935; Court Records: Criminal Records, Judgments, Clerks' Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Fiduciary Records; Tax and Fiscal Records. No chancery found.
- Records, 1889-1963
  County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records, 1889-1937 and 1960-1963 (payroll), Treasurer's Records, 1937; Fiduciary Records and Land Records: Deeds, 1889-1919; Court Records: Judgments, 1918-1944, Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes, 1928-1951, Chancery Records, 1946; Election Records, 1952-1954; Bonds, Commissions, Oaths, 1936-1947 (Special Police and Constable Appointments); Miscellaneous Records: Partial copy of Coalfield Progress, 1935 August 8.) Pre-1914 chancery pulled.
- Records, 1856-1932
  Court Records: Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes and Arrest Warrants, 1859-1860, Judgments, 1858-1924, Chancery Records, 1920 and 1927, Clerk's Records: Clerk's Correpondence, 1928; Miscellaneous Records: Powers of Attorney, 1856-1897 and 1923; Election Records (Big Stone Gap), 1905; Land Records: Deeds, 1920 and 1931; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records, 1911-1922, Board of Supervisors Records, 1930; Treasurers' Records, 1928 and 1932; Fiduciary Records, 1912 and 1919; Tax and Fiscal Records, 1928-1932 (Hunting and Fishing Licenses.)
- Records, 1850-1950
  Court Records: Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes, Jury Records: Grand Jury Presentments, Judgments, Chancery Records, 1920-1950; Land Records, 1890-1910; Tax and Fiscal Records: Commonwealth Claims; Election Records, 1905-1915; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths (includes loyalty oaths, 1866); Military and Pension Records (application for Union pension 1894); County Administrative Records: Treasurer's Record, 1904; Organization Records: Church Records (Methodist Woman's Home Missionary Society fundraising cards), 1904); Marriage Records and Vital Statistics: Marriage License. Pre-1913 Chancery Pulled.
- Records, circa 1899-1945
  Tax and Fiscal Records, 1899-1919; Military and Pension Records (list of persons registered for the draft), 1917; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, 1899-1904; Court Records: Judgments, circa 1900-1940, Chancery Records, 1917-1934, Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes, 1904-1945. Pre-1914 chancery pulled.
- Records, 1887-1910
  Tax and Fiscal Records, Court Records: Judgments, Criminal Records; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics, 1887-1894; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Military and Pension Records. Chancery pulled.
- Records, circa 1900-1980 (bulk 1900-1966)
  Court Records: Judgments, 1900-1966, 1980, Criminal Records, 1900-1942, Chancery Records, 1921-1960, Clerk's Records (memorandum book), 1970; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, circa 1900-1945; Fiduciary Records, 1914-1966; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics, 1924; Tax and Fiscal Records (Poll Tax Book, 1925). No pre-1914 chancery found.
- Records, 1885-1907
  Court Records: Judgments, Criminal Records; Tax and Fiscal: Claims. No chancery found.
- Records, 1857-1950
  Court Records: Criminal Records, 1857-1930, Judgments, 1890-1950; Tax and Fiscal Records, 1989-1910. No chancery found.
- Records, circa 1859-1955; 1979-1980
  Court Records: Judgments, 1859-1955, 1979-1980, Criminal Records, Chancery Records, circa 1915-1955; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Tax and Fiscal Records; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records, 1922; Miscellaneous Records: Powers of Attorney; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics: Marriage Licenses, 1922. Pre-1914 chancery pulled.
- Records, 1889-1969
  Court Records: Clerks' Records, 1904-1962 (includes annual reports, 1904-1910), Criminal Records, 1889-1950 (paroles, 1905-1950), Judgments, 1922; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records, 1919; Tax and Fiscal Records: Claims, 1919; Land Records: Deeds, 1969. Chancery pulled.
- Records, 1893-1959, undated
  Court Records: Judgments, 1893-1927, Criminal Records, 1908-1934, Chancery Records, 1925; Election Records, 1917-1932; Land Records, 1912-1924, 1959; Fiduciary Records: 1914-1917; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, 1918; Miscellaneous Records: Powers of Attorney, undated. Pre-1914 chancery pulled.
- Records, circa 1903-1949
  School Records; Court Records: Criminal Records, circa 1910-1940, Judgments, Chancery Records, 1940; Organization Records, 1903; Business Records, 1941-1942; Tax and Fiscal Records; County Administrative Records: Overseers of the Poor Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Fiduciary Records; Election Records, 1922-1925, 1949; Miscellaneous Records: Powers of Attorney. Pre-1913 chancery pulled.
- Records, 1885-1900
  Court Records: Judgments, Criminal Records, Clerk's Records; Land Records; Fidcuiary Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; County Administrativer Records: Overseers of the Poor Records, Treasurer's Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Election Records and Miscellaneous Records: Powers of Attorney. Chancery pulled.
- Records, circa 1875-1940
  Court Records: Abstracts of Judgments; County Administrativer Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Election Records.
- Records, 1890-1979
  Land Records: Deeds, 1890-1969; Fiduciary Records, 1925-1969; Court Records: Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes, 1900-1965, Judgments, 1907-1979, Chancery Records, 1934-1948, Clerks' Records, 1903-1916; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, 1931-1935; Tax and Fiscal Records, 1920-1933, Bear-Deer Damage Stamps, 1970-1971; Election Records, 1935; County Administrative Records: Treasurer's Records, 1933. Pre-1913 chancery removed.
- Records, 1885-1900
  Court Records: Criminal Records: Commonwealth Causes, Judgments: Civil Executions; Fiduciary Records.